（A24影业）
（切宁娱乐）
（21 Laps娱乐公司）
（原子怪兽影业）
出品公司
北路影业
A24影业
制作公司
21 Laps娱乐公司
原子怪兽影业
制作公司
福波斯
原创译制
蒙太奇字幕组
（异步研究所）
（基洛纳区调查：档案446 — 纳伦·沃恩
1990年6月19日
美国能源部）
好 好 好
Okay, okay, okay, okay...
没事的
Okay...
对 对
Yes... Yes...
对 对 快点 快点 没错 没错
Yes, yes, come on... Come on, yes! Yes, yes!
到了 到了 到了
Okay. Okay. Okay.
找到了 找到了
Here we go, here we go.
好 好 该死
Okay. Okay. Fuck.
能用 能用 一定得能用
Work. Work. Work.
基准组... 好...
Standard... Okay...
基准组 你们...你们能收到吗？
Standard, can you- can you hear me?
我是纳伦
This is Naren.
我 呃...
And I've, um...
我跟其他人走散了
I've been separated, uh, from the others.
我应该没事
And I think I'm okay,
我不知道我现在到底在哪儿
but I'm not sure where I, uh...
我从来没走到过这么深 所以我也...
I've never been out this far before, so I don't...
刚才有个...
There was this, uh...
我没看清 可是 呃...
I didn't get a good look at it, but there was, um...
这里还有别的东西
there's something else in here.
你们快来
I need you guys.
明白吗？快来接我 求你们了
Okay? I need you guys to get me, please.
该死 快来把我弄出去
Fuck, I need you guys to come out and get me.
麻烦来接我 求你们了 基准组
Can you... can you come, please, standard?
收到了吗？
Standard?
完了
Oh, fuck!
Fuck...
该死 该死
Fuck! Fuck...
该死 搞什么鬼？
Oh, shit... What the fuck?
（需无用信...）
怎么回事？
What the fuck?
完了 完了 完了
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
该死
Shit.
完了
Fuck!
不 不 完了 完了
Fuck, fuck, fuck! Fuck!
《后室》
（山脊公寓楼盘）
谁都有自己的死循环 固有的习惯...
We all have our loops, our habits...
总是重蹈覆辙...
...behaviors that keep us walking in circles...
总是用同样的办法 一遍又一遍
...reaching for the same solutions over and over again,
（克船长的家具帝国）
却指望能走出新路
thinking each time they'll take you somewhere new.
但没用
But they don't.
毕竟
And still,
神经通路就爱走阻力最小的路径
it's the neural pathway of least resistance.
（奸商）
你建立了心理防线
A path you made.
小时候 这套防线保护了你
It's the one that kept you safe when you were a child.
（全店促销 低价保证 全场清空 全场甩卖）
你学会了抢在被伤害之前
You learned to push people away
把别人推开
before they could hurt you.
现在
And now,
你都成年了
as an adult,
（逾期通知）
还是留在原地
you're still stuck right where you started.
只有一个人
Alone.
我有人陪啊
I mean, I'm not lonely.
我有店员 还有顾客
I have employees and... customers.
我没说有人陪 我说的是只有一个人
I didn't say lonely. I said alone.
好吧 是 但是...
Yeah, well, I mean...
我老是伤人
I hurt people.
我也不想 可我脑回路就是这样接的
I don't want to. It's just the way I'm wired.
可能就该把自己关起来
So maybe I deserve to be alone.
谁活该把自己关着吗？
Do you think anyone deserves to be alone?
我说不好 但怎么说呢
I don't know, but, you know,
也许这样也挺好
maybe it's not such a bad thing.
自我封闭...
Being alone feels...
已经刻进骨子里了
deeply ingrained.
我理解
I understand.
你有梦想 但老是受挫
You've had dreams and a lot of resistance,
身边也没人支持你
not a lot of support in realizing those dreams.
当伤害变成了...
And when we've experienced...
一次次家常便饭
hurt again and again,
你就会习惯性地想
we start to expect it.
“哦 这路我熟”
It's like, "Oh, I know this path.
“下场一定是一样的”
I know where it goes."
所以...
So...
你想不想摆脱这个死循环
are you interested in forging a new path
走出一条不同的路？
and see where that leads?
好啊
Sure.
我来都来了 就试试吧
Why not? You know, I'm here.
很好
Great.
要不咱们重温一下...
So I want to revisit
之前练过的那个...
an exercise we've done before.
角色扮演
The role play.
- 哦 演戏那套？ - 对
- Oh, the acting thing? - Yeah.
- 我觉得太丢人了 - 我懂
- I feel stupid doing that. - I know.
但既然还有点时间 就....
But we have a few minutes. Let's, um...
试一下吧 稍微试试
Yeah, let's try. A little bit.
好吧
All right.
咱们先定个场景
Let's set the scene.
回到芭芭拉离开你的那晚
Let's go back to the night that Barbara left you.
你是说她把我从我自己家给撵出去的那晚？
You mean the night she kicked me out of my own house?
对
Yeah.
我演我自己
I'm playing myself.
我演芭芭拉
And I'll be Barbara.
别忘了 那可是我的房子
It is my house, by the way.
房贷都是我在还
I'm the one paying for it.
- 我知道 - 好吧
- I know. - All right.
好 那...
Okay, so, um...
那天我回家晚了 具体几点我忘了
I got home late. I don't know how late.
那时候她已经睡了 应该是半夜了
Uh... She was already asleep. Maybe midnight.
她一般睡得早... 算了 这不重要
She usually goes to bed before... It doesn't matter.
重点是我当时在厨房 额...
The point is, I was in the kitchen, and, um...
有个杯子 我把杯子打碎了
the glass, I broke the glass, and...
她听见动静跑下来 然后...
she comes running down to see what happened, and...
就闹起来了
things escalated.
那你当时什么感受？
And how do you feel?
我当时...
Well, I was...
我当时喝多了...
I was drunk, and, um...
我 我觉得自己挺蠢的 你懂吧
I-I felt stupid, you know.
我就火了 因为...因为我把杯子打碎了
I was angry, because... because I broke the glass.
你能对着我再说一遍吗？
Can you say that to me?
- 对着你 对着芭芭拉？ - 对
- Uh, what, to-to Barbara? - Yeah.
对不起 把你吵醒了
Um... I'm sorry that I woke you.
要是你能早点回家
Maybe if you'd come home earlier,
咱们今晚本该待在一起的
we could have spent the evening together.
我 我在加班 你懂的
No, I was... I was working, you know?
下班后我就直接回来了
I came straight home after work.
诚实点吧
Be honest with me, please.
你身上那酒气我都闻得见
I can smell it on your breath.
我就去喝了一点啤酒
I had a few beers.
一点是多少？
Define a few.
唉 今天太累了
Well, it was a hard day.
我得喝点放松放松
I needed to wind down.
你不成天在放松吗？
All you ever do is wind down.
成天呆在那店里
You're always at the store.
你想要孩子 对吧？
You want kids, right?
- 咱们都想要 - 但你要知道...
- We both do. - Well, you know...
养孩子得花钱
having a family takes money,
总得有人去挣钱
which means someone has to work.
除非现在当学生
Unless being a professional student
也能算份工作了
is considered a job these days.
你不能这么说 你知道我得休学一段时间
That's not fair. You know I had to take time off.
你自己跟不上 凭什么怪我
Well, it's not my fault if you can't keep up.
连法学院都搞不定
How are you going to be a lawyer
还想怎么当律师？
if you can't even handle law school?
当你这个三十岁的“大一新生”
Who do you think pays for everything
在学校里到处瞎逛时
while you're gallivanting around campus
也不想想谁在供你上学？
like a 30-year-old freshman?
提示你一下 那就是我
I'll give you a hint: it's me.
你上学是我供 休学也是我供
I pay for your school, I pay for your time off school,
连住这儿都还是我在供
I pay for the roof over your head.
- 我能说句话吗？ - 不 我还没说完
- Can I talk now? - No! No.
我倒想知道 要是你真混到毕业了
Because I'd like to know, what do you think happens
又会发生什么？
if you do manage to graduate?
生个娃 然后继续把账单甩给我吗？
You know, you pop out a kid, then leave me with the bill.
还是你天天忙你的第一份工作
Or am I stuck at home changing diapers because
让我在家里给娃换屎尿？
you're too busy working for the first time in your life?
- 你这话太过分了 - 我只是说实话
- Now you're being cruel. - I'm being honest.
在我看来这就是你的追求
I thought that's what you always wanted.
你没考上建筑师 并不代表...
Just because you didn't get to be an architect doesn't mean--
老子就是建筑师！
I am a fucking architect!
我之所以得成天在那破店里卖这些玩意儿
God damn it, I'm just stuck selling shit furniture because
就是因为某个懒猪在家混吃等死 根本不肯出力
someone won't get off their fat fucking ass and help me!
克拉克 现在感觉怎么样？
How do you feel, Clark?
我在跟谁说话呢？
Who am I talking to?
- 和我 此刻 此地 - 哦 你啊 好吧
- Me, here, now. - You? Okay.
那个...
Um...
对不起 我不是有意说...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to, uh...
就是 刚才发火了
...you know, get angry
情绪失控了那种
or lose my temper or whatever.
我知道
I know.
练习的目的就在这儿
That's the purpose of the whole exercise.
这是一个不错的开始
This is a good start.
正视你的感受
To feel what you feel,
然后慢慢找出一条新路
and then learn to identify a new path.
你的反应其实很正常
Your reaction was actually quite normal.
呵呵 我就这德行
Well, that's me!
哟 伙计们 瞧瞧这儿啊！
Well, ahoy there, mateys!
还打算把金币全砸在那些冤大头家具上？
Tired of spending your hard-earned doubloons on overpriced furniture?
想买惊掉下巴的跳海价吗？
Looking for deals that'll shiver your timbers?
赶快来克船长的家具帝国！
Then come on down to Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire,
圣克拉拉谷的头号家具大卖场
the Santa Clara Valley's favorite warehouse and showrooms.
【圣克拉拉谷：位于美国西部】
卧室 客厅 餐厅 书房 浴室
You'll find bedrooms, living rooms,
全屋家具 应有尽有！
dinettes, dens and bathrooms aplenty.
刚买房的？来这儿就对了！
First-time homeowners? We've got ya.
新当爹妈的？
New parents looking for Billy's first crib?
来这就对了！
We've got ya!
时髦现代样样全
From the latest in modern design
经典复古通通有
to the classic styles of yesteryear,
价格低到没对手
it's all here and it's all a steal.
怎么啦 波莉？
What's that, Polly?
信用卡里钱不够？
You're worried about credit?
哈哈！在克船长这儿 钱不够 没问题！
Ha! Cap'n Clark says no credit, no problem!
快来畅游顶级家具海洋
Sail the high seas of high quality,
把钱的问题统统抛在脑后
and leave your money problems at the door.
今天就来店里
Walk in today
把梦想直接搬回家！
and get your dream sectional lounger,
桌椅板凳 灯具摆件随便挑！
kitchen table, floor lamp, and bed frame here
克船长的家具帝国
at Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire,
就在680号公路出口 国会路和麦基路口
located at Capitol and McKee, just off the 680.
嘿吼！赶紧过来...
Arr! Walk in today...
翘起二郎腿
...kick your feet back,
当你的家具大王！
and enjoy an empire of your own!
毕竟 国王得有王座
For every sultan deserves a throne,
而你的专属王座 就在这儿等着你
and we've got one with your name on it,
就在克船长的...
here at Cap'n Clark's--
卧槽
No way!
- 克拉克 没事吧？ - 快把相机关了
- Clark, you good? - Turn the camera off.
不不 拍得好 这种花絮才有趣
No, no, it's good. It's outtake stuff, dude.
- 赶紧给老子关掉 - 好吧...我的天
- Turn the fucking camera off. - Okay... Jesus...
那个 要帮忙吗？
You, uh, you need help?
不用 我自己来
No, I got it, I got it.
那个...
Um...
- 还要重拍吗？ - 不拍了
- Are we going again, or...? - No.
小凯 去开门营业吧
Kat, you can open the store now.
早就开了
We've been open.
（全店促销 低价保证 全场清空 全场甩卖）
老哥 我还是没搞懂
You know, dude, I still don't get it.
（结束南非种族隔离）
你演的是海盗还是国王？
Are you, like, a pirate or a sultan?
- 最好还是明确一下 - 我是个...闭嘴
- Just be good to establish it. - I'm a... Shut up.
（结束南非种族隔离）
刨花板做的破椅子
Piece of cheap particleboard bullshit.
快把这东西弄走 听到没？
Clear this stuff up, will you?
拿着
Here.
（全店促销 低价保证 全场清空 全场甩卖）
（1990年6月）
该死
Shit.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
怎么样 查出来没？
How's it looking?
电表没问题
Meter reads fine.
电费要是高 只能是你自己用得多
If your bill's coming in high, that's on you.
那跳电的事怎么说 打烊后就出现
What about the outages? That happens after hours.
没准是荧光灯出问题 导致跳闸了
Don't know. Fluorescents must be tripping a breaker.
但是一打烊我就把顶灯都关了
I turn the overheads off when the store closes,
还没闪之前就关了
before the power gets weird.
而且如果真是那样 电费不该更少吗？
Anyway, wouldn't that just make the bills go down?
配电箱在哪儿？
Where's your breaker box?
虽然我不是专家
I'm no expert,
但我之前看过了 没看出什么问题
but I checked earlier, and everything looks okay.
- 你说灯会闪 - 对 整个店都闪
- You said the lights flicker. - Yeah, the whole store does.
- 是吗？ - 只是不一起闪
- Huh. - Just not at the same time.
有一晚是楼上
One night, I lose the power upstairs.
下一晚就变成了楼下 完全没规律
Next night, it's down here. There's no rhyme or...
谁装的这鬼东西？
Who the hell installed this thing?
这房子买来时 回路就这样接的
Well, the building came wired.
虽然有点年头 但也不至于不能用
I mean, it's dated, but it's not that old.
你来看看这个
Take a look at this.
之前没这东西
That wasn't there before.
也许...
Or...
是我没注意到 我不是专家
maybe I didn't notice. Like I say, I'm no expert.
为...为什么是斜着的？
Why-why is it... why is it going that way?
应该问问
Better question:
这东西到底连到哪儿了
what is it even connected to?
懂吗？
Huh?
小凯 楼上灯怎么样？
Kat! How's the power?
干嘛？
What?
上面有反应吗？
Anything happen up there?
怎么搞的
What the hell?
老鼠又来了
The rat's back.
- 灯还正常吧 - 正常
- But the power's on. - Yeah.
我还以为咱们已经把老鼠给干掉了
I thought we killed the rat.
咱们才干掉了一只
We killed  "a"  rat.
- 这就是问题原因吗？ - 没道理啊
- So is this the problem? - Don't see how.
电路根本不走这里
Power can't even go through this part of the circuit.
它纯粹是...
It's just...
莫名其妙出现在这
there.
像被哪个笨蛋随便塞进去的
Like some schmo just stuck it in there.
没错
Yeah.
你是否觉得生活像被隔在了一层玻璃之后？
Do you ever feel like you're living behind glass?
看着世界在眼前上演
Watching life happen,
自己却只能旁观？
but never really stepping into it?
现在 是时候打开心灵之窗了
Maybe it's time to open the window within.
你可以重新定义自己的人生
You can be the author of your own design
我们每个人 都值得拥有另一次机会
because we all deserve another chance
让梦想重新启航
to fulfill our dreams.
只要你相信改变是可能的
The moment you believe change is possible,
你就已经开始了这段旅程
you've already begun.
立即订购《心灵之窗》
Order The Window Within
(《心灵之窗》)
以及配套的三辑音频课程
and the companion three-part audio program,
（突破障碍 掌控人生
打破那扇窗）
《引导之门》 均由玛丽·克莱因医生倾力呈现
Guided Openings, by Dr. Mary Klein.
（三辑音频课程）
现价24.95美元 运费另计
Available now for $24.95 plus shipping.
请拨打1-800-555-0199
Call 1-800-555-0199.
（克里斯·弗格森公司出品）
开辟一条新路 永远不晚
It's never too late to forge a new path.
【克里斯·弗格森：《后室》电影制片人】
“你居然还在信任纸质文件夹”
"So, you're still trusting paper folders,
“贴错标签的磁带 还有个谁拿把钥匙”
"mislabeled tapes, and a locked filing cabinet
“都能开的文件柜？”
"that anyone with a spare key can open?"
“信息决定企业的生死”
"Your business runs on information,
“但大多数公司却把数据当成了堆杂物...”
"yet most companies treat their data like clutter..."
那个信号不是小行星
That small blip is not an asteroid.
是一艘飞船 它咬住我们了
It's a spaceship, and it's on our tail.
（1970年圣克鲁斯现代主义建筑设计论坛）
- 它在靠近 - 不可能 里格娜
- It's getting closer. - Impossible, Rigna.
他们不可能发现我们 雷达隐身还开着呢
They couldn't have spotted us. We have our radar shield on.
我知道 长官 但他们追上来了
I know that, sir, but they are gaining on us.
难道地球人有某种秘密设备
Is it possible Earth has a secret device
能穿透我们的雷达隐身罩？
that can penetrate our radar shield?
垃圾
Piece of shit.
“为什么 你要这样对待自己？”
"Why did you do this to yourself?"
“你是怎么来到这里的？”
"How did you get here?"
“你的意识 就像一个装满记忆的房间”
"Your consciousness is a room full of memories
“它在时刻重构 在无限演变”
"that is constantly evolving."
（收音机 磁带）
“在现实生活中”
"But as you walk through life,
“缺乏引导的心灵会开始筑墙”
"the untrained mind can start to build walls,
“建立屏障”
"put up barriers
“隔绝外界”
"to protect itself from the outside world."
“这是本能反应”
"It's a natural response."
“我们常常对此毫无察觉”
"Something we are often unaware of."
“但久而久之”
"But if gone unchecked,
“你会发现 自己被囚禁了”
"it can leave you feeling trapped."
“你会说服自己”
"You can become convinced that the world outside
“外面的世界不需要你”
"is better off without you."
“你会告诉自己 自己不配被爱”
"That you never deserve the relationships you've had."
“于是 你只能蜷缩在窗后”
"Resigned to watch your life unfold
“当个旁观者 静静地看着生活上演”
"from behind a lone window."
“让我来帮你打开”
"I can help you open it now
“因为窗户根本没锁”
"because the window isn't locked."
“门也没有封死”
"The latch was never broken."
“准备好跨过去了吗？”
"Are you ready to step through?"
“去夺回属于你的东西”
"So that you can reclaim that which was once yours...
“去重新主宰你的生命”
"and take back control of your life."
“去过你想过的人生”
"The life you want to be living."
“卸下过去的重负”
"Unburdened by the traumas of the past."
“走出那些你亲手打造的围墙”
"Free of the confines you had built."
...所以我想...
...to leave, and so I decided...
“开辟一条属于你自己的路”
"And free to choose a path of your own design."
（家庭牙科诊所 米莱服饰）
（停）
“嘿 牛仔们 快瞧这边！”
"Well, hey there, cowboys and cowgirls!"
“想在格兰德河这块地盘”
"Are you looking to rustle up the best deals
【格兰德河：位于美国南部】
“抢到最便宜的家具吗？”
"this side of the Rio Grande?"
混球
Prick.
“咿吼！快来大韦恩家具店！”
"Well, yeehaw, I say yeehaw!"
“买了我们的餐厅套装”
"Here at Big Wayne's, our dining room sets
“就跟挖到金矿一样！”
"are gonna make you feel like you just struck gold."
“别去管那些破店”
"So don't even think about going anyplace else."
“认准大韦恩 认准金色招...”
"Big Wayne's, just look for the golden--"
（大韦恩家具店）
搞什么...
What the...
（由此下楼）
该死
Stupid...
看老子怎么修理你
Fuck! Piece of shit!
（亭亻）
（粤语）“各位好吗？祝各位平安健康快乐”
（阿卡德语）“愿一切都很好”
（俄语）“你好 欢迎你们”
（泰语）“远方土地的朋友们 你们好”
（泰语）“在这片土地上的我们 向你们所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（阿拉伯语）“我们向星际中的朋友们致以问候”
（阿拉伯语）“但愿时间能让我们相聚”
（罗马尼亚语）“向大家问好”
（法语）“大家好”
（缅甸语）“你们好吗？”
（希伯来语）“你好”
（西班牙语）“你好 向大家致敬”
（印尼语）“女士们先生们 晚上好”
（印尼语）“再见...”
有人吗？
Hello?
（克丘亚语）“用克丘亚语向你们”
（克丘亚语）“每一个人问好”
（旁遮普语）“欢迎你们”
（赫梯语）“你们好”
（孟加拉语）“你好 愿到处都有和平”
（拉丁语）“无论你们是谁 你们好”
（拉丁语）“我们对你们心怀善意”
（拉丁语）“并带着和平穿梭星际”
（亚兰语）“你好”
（荷兰语）“向每个人致以诚挚的问候”
（德语）“向所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（乌尔都语）“愿和平与你们同在”
（乌尔都语）“我们代表地球的居民”
（乌尔都语）“欢迎你们”
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck?
（越南语）“...致以友好的问候”
（土耳其语）“亲爱的说土耳其语的朋友们”
（土耳其语）“祝你们有个美好的早晨”
（日语）“你好 你们好吗？”
（印地语）“来自地球居民的问候”
（威尔士语）“祝你们现在及未来健康”
（意大利语）“致以最美好的祝愿和问候”
（僧伽罗语）“健康长寿”
（恩古尼语）“向伟大的你们致意”
（恩古尼语）“祝你们永恒繁荣”
（塞索托语）“向伟大的你们致以问候”
（吴语）“祝大家好”
（亚美尼亚语）“向宇宙中存在的...”
（亚美尼亚语）“所有生命致以问候”
（朝鲜语）“你们好”
（波兰语）“欢迎 来自异世界的生命”
（尼泊尔语）“地球人祝愿你们拥有一个和平的未来”
（汉语）“各位都好吧？我们都很想念你们”
（汉语）“有空请到这儿来玩”
（伊拉族语）“祝愿你们一切都好”
（瑞典语）“来自地球...”
（瑞典语）“伊萨卡小镇一名程序员的问候”
（齐切瓦语）“其他星球的朋友们 你们好吗？”
（古加拉特语）“地球人类向宇宙各处”
（古加拉特语）“致以诚挚问候”
（古加拉特语）“期待着收到你们的回复”
（乌克兰语）“来自我们世界的问候”
（乌克兰语）“祝愿你们幸福健康 长久繁荣”
（波斯语）“向遥远天际的....”
（奥里亚语）“来自太阳系第三颗行星...”
（奥里亚语）“地球的问候”
（干达语）“向宇宙所有族群致意”
（干达语）“愿和平永远伴随你们”
（马拉地语）“地球人民向你们传递美好的祝愿”
（台语）“太空的朋友们 你们好”
（台语）“吃过饭没？来我们这儿坐坐”
（异步研究所雇员 纳伦·沃恩）
（匈牙利语）“用匈牙利语向宇宙中所有热爱和平的生命致意”
（泰卢固语）“说泰卢固语的人们...”
有人吗？
Hello?
（捷克语）“亲爱的朋友们 祝你们万事如意”
（卡纳达语）“代表说卡纳达语的人们 向你们致以美好祝愿”
（拉贾斯坦语）“大家好 我们这里很幸福”
（拉贾斯坦语）“愿你们那里也同样幸福”
（英语）“来自地球儿童的问候”
"Hello from the children of planet Earth."
【多国语问候：源自1977年旅行者号金唱片】
（古希腊语）“你们好 无论你们是谁...”
（葡萄牙语）“愿所有人平安幸福”
（粤语）“各位好吗？祝各位平...”
哦...
Ooh...
（克丘亚语）“用克丘亚语向你们”
（克丘亚语）“每一个人问好”
（旁遮普语）“欢迎你们”
（赫梯语）“你们好”
（孟加拉语）“你好 愿到处都有和平”
（拉丁语）“无论你们是谁 你们好”
（拉丁语）“我们对你们心怀善意”
（拉丁语）“并带着和平穿梭星际”
（亚兰语）“你好”
（荷兰语）“向每个人致以诚挚的问候”
（德语）“向所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（乌尔都语）“愿和平与你们同在”
（乌尔都语）“我们代表地球的居民”
（乌尔都语）“欢迎你们”
（越南语）“诚挚地向你们致以友好的问候”
（土耳其语）“亲爱的说土耳其语的朋友们”
（土耳其语）“祝你们有个美好的早晨”
（日语）“你好 你们好吗？”
（印地语）“来自地球居民的问候”
（威尔士语）“祝你们现在及未来健康”
（意大利语）“致以最美好的祝愿和问候”
（僧伽罗语）“健康长寿”
（恩古尼语）“向伟大的你们致意”
（恩古尼语）“祝你们永恒繁荣”
（塞索托语）“向伟大的你们致以问候”
（吴语）“祝大家好”
（亚美尼亚语）“向宇宙中存在的...”
（亚美尼亚语）“所有生命致以问候”
（朝鲜语）“你们好”
（波兰语）“欢迎 来自异世界的生命”
（尼泊尔语）“地球人祝愿你们拥有一个和平的未来”
（汉语）“各位都好吧？我们都很想念你们”
（汉语）“有空请到这儿来玩”
（伊拉族语）“祝愿你们一切都好”
（瑞典语）“来自地球...”
（瑞典语）“伊萨卡小镇一名程序员的问候”
（齐切瓦语）“其他星球的朋友们...”
是谁啊？
Anyone there?
哦 该死...
Oh, fuck...
（亭亻）
好 好
Okay, Okay...
（法语）“大家好”
（缅甸语）“你们好吗？”
（希伯来语）“你好”
（西班牙语）“你好 向大家致敬”
（印尼语）“女士们先生们 晚上好”
（印尼语）“再见期待下次再见”
（克丘亚语）“用克丘亚语向你们”
（克丘亚语）“每一个人问好”
（旁遮普语）“欢迎你们”
（赫梯语）“你们好”
（孟加拉语）“你好 愿到处都有和平”
（拉丁语）“无论你们是谁 你们好”
（拉丁语）“我们对你们心怀善意”
（左声道 右声道）
（拉丁语）“并带着和平穿梭星际”
（亚兰语）“你好”
（基洛纳区-监视点J3 1990年6月29日）
（荷兰语）“向每个人致以诚挚的问候”
（德语）“向所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（乌尔都语）“愿和平与你们同在”
（乌尔都语）“我们代表地球的居民”
（乌尔都语）“欢迎你们”
抱歉来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
路上堵死了 我又没法提前走
Traffic was hell, and I couldn't leave early.
没关系 趁还有时间聊聊吧
Let's just use the time we have.
今天感觉怎么样 克拉克？
How are you today, Clark?
你觉得呢 我看起来怎么样？
How do I look?
挺好的 可能有点累吧
Fine. A little tired, maybe.
我简直糟糕透了
I look like shit.
我想确认一下
Can I ask, and there is
放心回答 没什么对错
no wrong answer here, you know that...
你现在是不是有一点喝醉了？
Are you intoxicated right now?
你干嘛这么问？
Why you say it like that?
怎么问了？
Like what?
我从周五起就没碰过一滴酒
I haven't had a drink since Friday.
没准儿我这副鬼样子就是因为没喝酒
It's probably why I look like shit.
- 我能问你个事吗？ - 请说
- Can I ask you something? - Sure.
你把人强制关精神病院过吗？
You ever 5150'd someone?
【加州法律5150条：强制将危险精神病人送院观察】
这么多年确实有过几次 只要情况需要
A few times over the years, when it was necessary.
那...那...那什么样的情况才算需要？
Wh-wha-what makes it necessary?
只要我认为对方有伤人自残的风险
If I believe that the person is a danger to themselves or others,
或者无法自理
or they're gravely disabled.
行
Okay.
那个...
Um...
我在店里发现了点情况
I found something in the store.
好 什么情况
Okay. What did you find?
呃...
Uh...
是个地方 我...
A place. I f...
我发现了个地方
I found a place.
地方？
A place?
嗯 感觉...
Yeah. It's like, um...
感觉店就那样...
It's like the store just, uh...
往外扩了
continues, I guess.
你知道吧...店有墙
It's like... you know, like there's a wall
墙后头居然还是店
and on the other side of the wall,
没完没了地往外扩
the store just keeps going, you know,
就像 就像 像个克隆的
like-like a... like a copy of itself.
我...我猜入口是用镜子什么的给挡住的
I-I-I figure they're using mirrors or something
我不确定
to hide the entrance, I don't know.
不好意思 我没听明白
Sorry, I'm not following you.
你是说找到了个之前没发现的房间？
Is this a room you didn't know about before?
不是
No.
就是...就是你一进去后
Okay, so y-y-you go in and, uh...
看着像个...像个写字楼
at first it just looks like a- like an office building.
一个巨大的办公室 你懂吧？
Like a... like a huge office building, you know?
然后...你 你继续往里走
And then, uh... But then you-you keep going,
接着...接着你就发现
and then-then you realize
所...所有东西都不对劲
th-th-that none of it makes any sense.
怎..怎么说呢...想象一下
It's-it's like, um... Imagine describing a dog
你给个没见过狗的人形容狗
to someone who's never seen one before
然后让那人把狗画出来
and then asking them to draw it.
可能会画对几个地方
They might get some things right, you know,
但绝不可能全画对
but there's no way they'd get everything right.
你知道 诡异的在于细节
You know, the devil's in the details.
所以远看像只狗
So from a distance, you look at it,
但凑近一看...
you think you're seeing a dog, but then you look clos--
干嘛那样看我？
Why are you looking at me like that?
我只是在试着理解
I'm just trying to understand.
呵
Oh.
你不像个心理医生 怎么表情都写在脸上
You know, for a shrink, you got a terrible poker face.
你说的这些听起来很离奇
What you're saying might sound fantastical,
但并不危险
but not dangerous.
那些办公室里有人吗？
Are there any people in these offices?
没见过 但我能听到
Not that I've seen. You know, I hear, um...
听到脚步声 而且...而且我一转眼
There's footsteps, an-an-and stuff gets moved around
东西就被挪了位置
when I'm not looking.
我知道这听起来很离谱 但你得明白
I know how this sounds, but you've got to understand,
那地方太大了
it's massive in there.
简直像纽约地铁那么大 懂吧
Like New-York's-subway-system massive, you know.
没准儿里面有好几百人
For all I know, there's hundreds of people.
我只是没看到
I just haven't seen them.
看
Look.
你看 这就像个...
You see? It's like a...
就像个迷宫
It's like a maze.
根本没尽头
It just goes on and on and on.
我有时候真怕自己会迷路
Sometimes I'm scared I'll get lost.
那为什么除了你 没人发现这地方？
Why do you think no one else has found this place?
我哪知道
I don't know.
但入口在负一层
The entrance is on the subfloor,
所以整个结构估计都在地下 懂吧
so the whole structure is probably underground, you know?
地图上根本没这个地方
It's not on any city maps.
入口根本看不出来 谁会想到去找？
The entrances are hidden, so who'd think to look?
我没说不信你...
I'm not saying I don't believe you...
不过 你跟我说
but you told me yourself
你周五就开始戒酒了
you haven't had a drink since Friday.
- 这会不会导致幻... - 行了
- Do you think there is a-- - Okay.
【译注：戒断反应可能产生幻觉】
- 克拉克 - 停 停
- Clark-- - No, no.
- 如果这是真的... - 行 我懂了 多谢您啊
- If this is true-- - Yeah, I get it. Thank you.
我迟早会带着证据回来
You know, I'm gonna come back here with proof
到时候你得给我好好道歉
and you're gonna owe me a serious fucking apology.
小凯
Kat!
那么早谁呀 来了 来了
Jesus, goddamn, I'm coming! I'm coming!
- 嘿 - 克船长？
- Hey. - Cap'n Clark?
- 额... - 等等 等等 小凯 快来
- Um... - Wait, wait, wait, wait. Kat?
- 我来了 - 快点
- I'm coming. - Kat!
行了 我来了
Okay, I'm coming!
- 是这样的... - 搞什么鬼
- Look-- -What the fuck?
抱歉 那个...
Yeah, I'm sorry, uh...
你们明天有空吗？
What are you guys doing tomorrow?
你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
我给钱 算加班 顶多两个小时 很快的
I'll pay you. Two hours. Overtime. Tops.
行 给钱干什么？
Okay, pay us for what?
做调研
Research.
摄像机还在你们那儿吧？
You got the camera, right?
你们能...能再帮我拍点东西吗？
You can-you can borrow it again...
行不行？
Right?
好了 开始拍了
Okay, we are rolling.
这儿摆了些东西
We got, um, some shit over here.
（亭亻）
还有停车牌
We got some stop signs
还有 呃 绳子
and, uh... a rope.
拿绳子干嘛？
What's the rope for?
装备
Supplies.
呵呵 看来咱们要被他绑了
Oh, great, he's gonna tie us up.
不是我绑 是要给自己绑好
No, we're gonna tie ourselves up.
唔 挺重口味的
Hmm. Kinky.
你胡说什么
What the fuck?
呃 你还没说清楚
Uh, you still haven't told us
我们来这儿干嘛？
what we're doing here, man.
我说了 做调研
I did tell you. Research.
这些是调研装备
These are supplies, and we're using them for research.
没那么难理解吧
It's not that hard to understand.
行 研究什么？
Okay, research for what?
你得具体点 老哥
Y-you gotta be more specific, dude.
我要进门了
I'm gonna go through the door.
什么门？
What door?
这就是门
That's the door.
我在另一边也贴了框
I taped an outline on the other side, too,
以防咱们找不到
just to help us find our way back.
- 阿博？ - 怎么了？
- Bobby? - What?
听着 我知道这很离谱 但得听我的
Look, I know it sounds crazy, but follow my lead.
懂吗？
Okay?
我想在天亮前赶回来
I want to be back before sunup.
老哥 现在才晚上九点 你说什么...
Dude, it's like 9 p.m. What the fuck are you talk--
- 什么情况 克拉克 - 卧槽
- What the fuck! Clark?! - What the fuck?
- 怎么做到的？ - 老哥 你...
- How did you do that? - Dude, did you...
你也看到了吧？他怎...怎么会...
Did you fucking see that?! H-how did he, um...
我就在这儿 快进来看看
I'm right here. Come see for yourself.
搞什么鬼 你居...居然真的...
What the fuck? D-did you just fucking...
什么？怎么会...
What? How the f...
你干嘛呢？阿博 快住手
Bobby, stop. What are you doing?
- 卧槽 - 克拉克 你在哪儿？
- What the fuck?! - Clark, where are you?
哈哈 你...你看到了没？
Ha! Hey, did you... did you see that?
- 他钻哪去了？ - 看到了 阿博 我看到了
- Where the fuck did he go? - Yes, Bobby, I saw it!
我去 搞什...
Oh! Where the f--
踏进来就行 没事的
Just step through the door, you'll be fine!
疯了吧 你得先解释清楚
What?! No! Tell us what is going on!
管他呢 直接...
You know what, just...
不 阿博 别进去 阿博 快停下 你要干什么？
No, Bobby, wait! Bobby! Wait, what are you doing?
阿博
Bobby!
我去啊
What the fuck?!
老哥
Dude!
老哥 这怎么可能？
Dude, how is this possible?
- 阿博 克拉克 - 行...
- Bobby! Clark! - Okay...
你们在哪？里面到底是什么地方？
Where are you? What the fuck is back there?
没事没事 小凯 没事的
No, no, no, Kat, it's good, it's good.
赶紧...赶紧进来看看
J-just, you gotta come see this.
我是说...对 你看...
I mean... Right, you see...
你看这 呃...
You see, it's, um...
- 没问题 - 克拉克 这是什么地方？
- It's fine. - Clark, what is this?
- 我们在哪？ - 哦
- Where are we? - Oh!
我也正想弄明白呢
That's what I'm trying to figure out.
这...这是谁的破烂？
Whose, um... Whose shit is this?
是你...是你店里的吗？
Is it-is it... is it part of your store?
如果真有主人的话
If it belongs to someone,
- 我还没碰到那个人 - 好吧
- I haven't met them yet. - Okay...
自从发现这地方 我每晚都来
I've been in here every night since I found the place,
但也就看了个冰山一角
and I still barely scratched the surface.
走 我带你们看看
Come on. I'll show you.
越往后越有意思
It only gets better.
- 真扯... - 嘿 嘿
- What the fuck... - Hey. Hey.
他别给咱们下药了吧？
You don't think he, like, dosed us or something, do you?
药？没那回事 咱们没嗑药
What? No, no, no. We're not on drugs.
要是嗨了 我肯定能感觉到
I think I'd be able to tell if I was high.
你现在就嗨着呢
You are high!
哈草不算
Pot doesn't count.
所以...这就像...
So, um, it's like...
像个空办公区？
what, like an empty office building?
在这儿？算是吧 但这地方简直像是
In here? Sure. But it's like it was made
一帮嗑嗨了的建筑工盖出来的
by a bunch of construction workers on acid.
居然还搞了个泳池
There's even a pool!
有泳池？
There's a pool?
没错 算是吧
Yeah. I mean, kind of.
快跟上
Keep up.
（亭亻）
倒着的“停”什么鬼？
"Pots." What the fuck?
不不不 那是我上次走的路
Yeah, no, no, that's the way I went last time.
当时我想找个楼梯下去什么的
Yeah, when I was looking for a staircase down or something.
结果只发现了个...
Only thing I found so far is basically more of a...
好的...
Okay...
怎么说呢 其实就是个斜坡
I don't know, it's like a ramp, really.
就在这儿...就在前面
It's, uh... It's up here.
马上就到了
We'll be at it in a minute.
好吧
Okay...
这下面总共有多少层？
How many floors does it go down?
怎么能挖...
Is this not technically...
行了 开始拍了吗？
Okay. All right, you filming?
- 拍了  - 行
- Yeah. - All right.
为什么非得让阿博下去？
I don't see why Bobby has to be the one to go.
- 我想去 - 摄像机在他手上
- I want to. - He's the one with the camera.
相机又没长在他身上
Well, it's not like it's attached.
它挂在我学生证上的 所以就算长在身上了
Yeah, well, I mean, to my student ID, yeah, it kinda is.
要是觉得不对劲 就拽一下 我把你拉上来 明白吧？
Any trouble, just give a tug, and I'll pull you up, okay?
不对劲？克拉克 下面有什么不对劲？
Trouble? Clark, what fucking trouble?
不会有事的
There's not going to be any trouble.
宝贝 宝贝 没事
Babe, babe, babe, it's good.
- 别下... - 真的没事 我没问题
- No, hey-- - It's good. I'm good.
亲爱的 你不用下去
Baby, you don't have to do this.
没事 我就是想看看下面有什么
No, it's cool. I-I just want to see what's down there.
- 你不好奇吗？ - 简直是疯了
- Are you not curious? - This is stupid!
- 能走多远就走多远 - 没事 你看 你看
- Just go as far as you can. - No, look, look, look!
其实不用绳子也能走下去
You can basically walk down without a rope.
没什么 一点也不陡
It's fine, and it's not even steep.
行吧
Okay.
好 但有一件事
Okay, just don't... just one thing.
万一我回不来 记得告诉我妈我爱她哦
If I don't come back, you'll tell my mom I love her, right?
- 行 - 那么 走吧
- Okay. - All right, okay.
好 慢慢来
All right, just take it slow.
行
Okay.
哦 实际上还挺陡的
Oh, it is actually kind of steep.
- 没问题吧？ - 没问题
- You good? - Yeah.
- 拉紧点 别把我摔了 - 放心
- Just, uh... try not to drop me. - All right.
要放绳子告诉我
Tell me how much you need.
喔...慢点
Whoa... Careful!
搞什么...喔 喔 喔 操 啊
What the... Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Fuck! Aah...
你会不会放绳子
What the fuck are you guys doing up there?
对不起 对不起
Sorry, sorry!
绳子绕到床腿上了
It was stuck around the leg of the bed!
- 你没事吧？ - 行 没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
真是绝了
Jesus fucking Christ...
继续放绳子
Just keep letting me down!
好的 来了
All right. Here we go.
好了 我下来了
Okay, I'm in.
看到什么没？
See anything?
呃...
Ugh...
呃 就是...
Uh, it's just...
就是一堆脏衣服和垃圾
It's a bunch of laundry and shit.
什么意思？衣服？
What do you mean? Clothes?
对 这下面真是臭死了
Yeah, it just fucking stinks down here.
还有什么吗？
See anything else?
有 呃...给我点时间
Yeah, just, uh... Just give me a minute.
好的
Okay.
真乱
Oh, god...
（结束南非种族隔离）
还撞衫了？
What the fuck?
阿博？
Bobby?
怎么了
Yeah.
就想确认下你没事
Just checking that you're okay.
嗯 我没事 只是 呃...
Yeah, I'm fine. Just, um...
好吧
Okay...
嗯
Yeah.
没问题
Okay.
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck...?
阿博？快上来
Bobby? Come back up!
我心里发毛
I don't like this!
嘿 呃...再多放点绳子
Hey! Uh... Let some more line out!
不行 已经到头了
I can't! It's as far as it goes.
该死
Fuck...
卧槽 卧槽 卧槽
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
快拉我上去 拉我上去 快
Pull me up! Pull me up! Pull me up!
阿博 怎么了？
Bobby! What is it?
- 操 - 你看到了什么？
- Fuck! - What do you see?
磨蹭什么 快把他拉上来
What the fuck is it? Pull him up!
- 我在拉啊 我的天 - 操
- I am! Jesus Christ! - Fuck!
拉快点
Pull harder!
快拉 老哥 搞什么鬼
Pull, man! What the fuck!
- 绳子绕到我脚上了 - 操
- It's getting caught on my feet! - Fuck!
- 绳子绕到... - 快点使劲拉
- I can't pull-- - Fucking pull harder!
克拉克 快点拉
Clark, hurry up!
快到了 快到了 宝贝 坚持住
Almost here! Almost here, babe, just a little more!
- 快把他拉上来 - 你看到了什么？
- Pull him up! - What did you see?
- 下...下面有人 - 你安全了...
- There's, uh, there's someone down there. - We've got you--
- 什么？- 操
- What? - Fuck.
慢点说 深呼吸 宝贝 没事了
Slow down, just breathe. Baby, it's okay.
快把这破玩意儿给我解开 操 真是够了
Just get this shit off me, man. Fuck. Jesus.
- 没事了 没事了 来 - 你看到了什么？
- It's okay. It's okay. Here. - What did you see?
- 深呼吸 - 这打的什么破结？
- Hey, deep breath. - What kind of knot is this?
- 卧槽 - 哎 哎 哎
- What the fuck?! - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 快救命 克拉克 - 抓紧我
- Help us! Clark! - Hold on!
- 来了 来了 来了 - 救人啊 你个混蛋
- Okay, okay, okay! - Help, you fucking asshole!
- 让我解 - 快给我解开 老哥
- Let me get it! - Untie me, man!
克拉克 你特么在磨蹭什么？
What the hell are you doing, Clark?
- 我解不开 - 快点 克拉克
- I can't! - Hurry, Clark!
- 我在弄了 我在弄了 - 操
- I'm trying, I'm trying! - FUCK!
别松手 别松手
Don't let go! Don't let go!
- 坚持住 - 操 千万别放手
- Hold on! - Fuck! Don't let me go!
- 千万别放手 - 我去拿...
- Don't let me go! - Let me get at--
阿博！
BOBBY!
不 小凯 不
NO! KAT, NO!
阿博
Bobby!
阿博！
BOBBY!
阿博
Bobby!
怎么回事 我们得...克拉克
What are we doing? We need to... Clark!
阿博 别 别 别
Bobby! No! No! No!
别 小凯 小凯
Ow... KAT! Kat...
阿博
Bobby!
阿博 不
Bobby! No!
小凯
Kat!
哦 该死
Oh, fuck...
哦 不 不 不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no! No!
小凯？
Kat?!
Kat?
有人吗？
Hello?
别过来 滚开
Stay back! Get away from me!
（麦基路）
克拉克？克拉克
Clark? CLARK!
我在这儿...
I'm here...
就在这 那东西要回来了
I'm here! It's gonna come back.
快让我进去 克拉克 求你让我进去
Please, Clark, please let me in!
- 小凯？ - 让我进去
- Kat? - Let me in!
你...你在在哪？
Wh-wh-where are you?
我们得赶紧走 克拉克 没时间了
We have to go now, Clark! We have to go.
- 那东西要回来了 它会找到我的 - 小凯 小凯？额...
- It's gonna come back, it's gonna find me! - Kat! Kat? Uh...
等等 我没搞明白 你到底在哪？
Wait, I don't understand. Wh-where are you?
求你了 赶紧让我进去
Please, let me the fuck in!
但这...这是堵墙啊
But it's a... it's-it's a wall!
你怎么能看到我？
How can-how can you see me?
我在玻璃的另一边
I'm on the other side of the glass.
你怎么看不见我？
How can you not see me?
什么玻璃？你在说什么鬼话？
What glass?! What the fuck are you talking about?
你在...在说什...？
Wh-what are you talk--
好吧 你那边能看到什么吗？
Okay, can you see anything on your side?
有门把手吗 还是有门？有没有入口之类的东西？
Can you see a handle, a door? Is there a hatch, anything?
没有 没有 没有...
No, no, no, no...
呃...好吧 让我想想办法 好吗？等一下
Uh... Okay. Let me figure this out, okay? Just hold on.
坚持住 行吗？只是...
Hold on, okay? It's just...
- 克拉克？ - 别急 别急 让我试...
- Clark? - No, no, just let me...
- 克拉克 - 别急
- Clark! - Just hold on!
- 我找找看 - 克拉克！
- Let me figure this out! - CLARK!
- 别催我 我在想办法 - 克拉克 快跑
- Let me figure this out... - Clark! Clark!
克拉克 它就在你身后
Clark, behind you!
（诺拉·克莱...
氯丙...）
【氯丙嗪：抗精神病药物】
玛丽 住手
Mary!
玛丽
Mary...
你疯了吗？
what were you thinking?
我说过绝对 绝对
I never, ever,
绝对不能出门
ever said you could go outside.
绝对不行
It's no good.
外面到处都是
They're all over the place.
“您拨打的是玛丽·克莱因医生的电话”
"Hi, you've reached Dr. Mary Klein."
“我目前不便接听”
"I'm not able to answer the call,
“请留言”
"so please leave a message,
“我会尽快给您回电”
"and I'll get back to you as soon as I can."
“玛丽...”
"Mary...
“我打开那扇窗了”
"I opened the window."
“我不会再回来了”
"I won't be coming back."
（克船长的家具帝国）
“...求你了”
"...Please!"
“救救我们”
"Save us!"
[（1983年 异步研究所获得120万美元联邦资助开发下一代核磁共振设备）]
“好 我照做”
"All right! I'll do it!
“我会救你们 我会照做”
I'll save you! I will do it!"
“梦翠儿！”
"Moon Child!"
【电影《大魔域》1984：讲述一个男孩通过想象力重建世界的奇幻故事】
谁知道你手之前碰过什么
I don't know where that hand's been.
【《大魔域》英文片名：直译为“永不结束的故事”】
“哟 伙计们 瞧瞧这儿啊！”
"Well, ahoy there, mateys!"
“按照这藏宝图”
"Now, according to me map,
“咱们现在已经登上了这片宝地”
"we've landed on the crystal shores of a bountiful land,
“这里的折扣简直是在倒贴啊！”
"a land filled with great deals."
“你也赶紧赶紧抛锚靠岸！”
"So drop your anchors and come on down
（圣克拉拉谷最低价
地址国会路与麦基路口）
“快来克船长的家具帝国！”
"to Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire."
“潜入这顶级家具的海洋吧”
"Get lost in an endless sea
“桌椅沙发 卧室全套 样样齐全！”
"of quality tables, chairs, couches, and bedroom sets."
（地址国会路与麦基路口）
“想给小海盗们配上下铺？”
"Need bed bunks for the scallywagses quarters?
“来这儿就对了！”
"W've got it all!"
“价格低到...”
"And at prices so low
“你都觉得在抢我的钱啊！”
"you'll think that yo're robbing me!"
有人吗？
Hello?
（全店促销 低价保证 全场清空 全场甩卖）
有人吗？
Hello?
（全店促销 低价保证 全场清空 全场甩卖）
克拉克？
Clark?
（无需信用卡）
克拉克 你在哪儿？
Clark, can you hear me?
（由此下楼）
克拉克？
Clark?
（亭亻）
（门 和 家具店）
克拉克？
Clark?
（平面图又变了 屋顶不对 屋顶绝对不对）
（这图纸是谁签的名？但这笔迹 像我的）
（管他的什么超自然 理智点吧）
（此刻和此地是相通的）
克拉克？
Clark?
你总算发现了
You found it.
你怎么不出来？
Why are you hiding?
你太刺耳了
You were being too loud.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
这里...
It's...
是所有存在过的地方
...every place that ever was.
你在这儿多久了？
How long have you been here?
什么声音？
What was that?
别紧张
Stay calm.
这里只有我
It's only me.
你认得我
You know me.
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
这全是为你好
This is for your own good.
在现实生活中
As you walk through life,
缺乏引导的心灵 总会走入死循环 养成固有的习惯
the untrained mind accumulates loops, habits...
总是重蹈覆辙
...behaviors that keep you drifting in circles,
陷入相同的问题
creating the same problems,
总是用同样的办法
reaching for the same solutions
一遍又一遍
over and over again.
毕竟神经通路就爱走阻力最小的路径
Still, it's the neural pathway of least resistance.
这条路径是我自己铺的
The one I made.
小时候
The one that kept me safe...
这套防线保护了我
when I was a child.
你看...
You know...
我学会了抢在被伤害之前 把别人推开
I learned to push people away before they could hurt me.
而现在 我都成年了
And, now, as an adult,
还是留在原地
I'm still stuck right where I started.
只有一个人
Alone.
怎么回事？
What is this?
真是一团糟 对吧？
It's a real mess. Am I right?
克拉克...
Clark...
让我来帮你...
...let me help you...
在你做出无法挽回的事之前
before you do anything you can't take back.
回答我的问题
Answer the question.
是的 真是一团糟
Yes, it's a real mess.
但从某种角度看 也很美
But also beautiful in a way.
不是吗？
No?
这些人是谁？
Who are these people?
这地方造了他们
This place builds them.
哦 其实更像是在记得他们
Oh, actually, more like it remembers them.
只不过记得越多
And the more times it remembers something,
就越走样
the less it does.
这个在外面是个穿条纹衫的家伙
Somewhere out there is a guy in a striped shirt,
但在这儿...
but, in here, he's...
他被记成了这样
remembered.
有点走样
Just slightly wrong.
这个在外面是个...
Somewhere out there is a man
坐轮椅的家伙 带了盏灯
in a wheelchair, and a lamp.
我敢说 这里就是这么回事
I'm pretty sure that's how you get all of this.
所有这些地方啊
You know, all these places
房间和建筑啊
and rooms and buildings
全都记岔了
misremembering themselves.
克拉克...
Clark...
我们好好谈谈吧
let's talk this through.
换个角度看...
In some ways...
他们甚至比原件更好
they're an improvement on the originals.
比如...
For starters,
他们没有任何感觉
they can't feel anything.
想象一下 那样得有多自在啊
Can you imagine how good that must feel?
我是说...
I mean...
没念头 没痛苦 没自我...
...there's no thoughts or pain, no ego...
也没恐惧
...no fear.
纯粹就是...
They simply...
在那儿
exist.
就像...就像家具一样
Like... like furniture!
看这儿 最绝的来了
Look at this. The best part.
他们能吃
You can eat them!
这是我的 呃...
That's my, uh...
助理
assistant manager.
我想帮她 但她就是...
I tried to help her, but she just, uh...
克拉克
Clark!
你把我解开 我们可以聊聊
If you untie me, we can talk this through,
让你心里好受点
get you feeling better.
是吗 就算解开了
Yeah, well, what if I did untie you?
那又怎样？
You know, what then?
你顶多像个
You'd run around here
没头苍蝇一样到处乱窜
like a chicken with its head cut off,
找你的出口
looking for a way out.
但你最后还是得回到这儿
But you'd end up in the same place you are now.
就跟你爱说的那套路径理论一样
Like the path thing you're always talking about.
克拉克
Clark!
我是真的想帮你 只要告诉我你想要什么
I just want to help you. Just tell me what you need.
我...我...我一定照做
I'll-I'll-I'll do it.
是吗？
Yeah?
是的 是的 拜托了
Yeah. Yes, please.
行
Okay.
我想听你亲口说
Well, I want you to tell me
我没做错任何事
that I didn't do anything wrong, you know,
是你之前对我看走眼了
that-that you were wrong about me.
是我看走眼了 是我错了
I was wrong about you! I was.
- 我真的看错你了 - 不 不 不要这样
- I was wrong about you. - No, no, not-not like that.
别 别这么快 好吗？
Not... not so fast, okay?
我的意思是 我想...我想先定个场景
I mean, I wanna... I want to set the scene first!
咱们从...
Let's start, um...
嗯...从那晚开始
well, the night that, uh...
就是我被撵出我自己家的那晚
that I got kicked out of my own house.
怎么样？
Yeah?
那天 嗯...很晚了
It was, um... It was late.
屋里很暗
A lot darker.
呃...
Uh...
关下灯
Lights, please.
之前跟她试过
I tried this exercise with her before.
她根本不会动 结果都一样
It doesn't go anywhere.
行
Fine!
我自己来
I'll do it myself.
毕竟 这终究还是我的房子
It's still my house after all.
好了
Yeah.
谢谢 这样才对
Thank you. Much better.
不过...
But there's...
还是...
still...
缺点儿什么
something off.
克拉克 求你..
Clark, please...
不 拜托 不要 不要...
No, please, don't, don't...!
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 我...
I'm sorry, I...
把杯子打碎了 还把你吵醒了
broke the glass and woke you up.
我知道你睡得早
I know how you like to sleep early.
我在店里忙太久了
I was at the store late.
就忘了时间
I guess I lost track of the time.
我之前在对账
I was checking inventory.
然后...
But...
顺路去喝了一点啤酒
I stopped off for a few beers.
- 克拉克 - 芭芭拉
- Clark-- - Barbara!
我之前在对账
I was checking inventory.
然后顺路去喝了一点啤酒
Then I stopped off for a few beers.
一点...一点是多少？
Defi-define a few.
我想喝多少就喝多少
As many as I wanted.
因为这房子是我的
Because this is my house.
房贷都是我在还
I pay for it.
所有的钱都是我在出 你上学是我供
I pay for everything. I pay for you to go to school.
休学也是我供
I pay for your time off school!
连住这儿都是我在供
I pay for the roof over your head!
你想要孩子 对吧？
You want kids, right?
养孩子得花钱
Well, that takes money.
总得有人去挣钱
So someone has to work around here.
我说过了这儿得有人干活
I said someone has
不能在那儿当个懒猪混吃等死
to get off her fat ass and work around here!
你没考上建筑师 并不代表...
Just because you didn't get to be an architect don--
老子就是建筑师
I am a fucking architect.
我之所以得成天在那破店里卖这些玩意儿
I'm just stuck selling shit furniture because someone
就是因为某个懒猪在家混吃等死 根本不肯出力！
won't get off her fat fucking ass and help me!
- 我才不是你老婆 - 别出戏
- I'm not your wife! - Stay in character.
继续演
Stay in character!
- 我压根就没见过她 - 继续演你的角色
- I've never even met her! - STAY IN CHARACTER!
滚你妈的蛋！
FUCK YOU!
你说什么？
What did you say?
你想知道为什么你老婆甩了你吗？
You wanna know the real reason your wife left you?
根本不是因为酗酒
It wasn't the drinking,
不是半夜烂醉回家 甚至不是你的坏脾气
or the stumbling home at all hours, or the rage.
是因为你是个巨婴
It was the whining!
你这辈子没一件事是你的错 对吧？
Nothing's ever your fault, is it?
喝多了 赖工作
You drink too much? Blame your job.
恨职业 赖世界
You hate your job? Blame the world.
被撵出家门
You get kicked out of the house?
赖老婆
Blame your wife.
现在你攻击我 绑架我
You attack me and tie me up?
就去赖你的脑子！
Blame your brain!
你这颗烂脑子 就是你本人 废物
You are your fucking brain, you dipshit!
- 所以 全都是我的错？ - 是啊
- You're saying it's my fault? - Yes!
但你肯定又要赖你的脑回路 对吧？
But it's just the way you're wired, isn't it?
对不对！
ISN'T IT?!
那我怎么才能停下来？
How do I stop doing that?
实话实说 我一丁点的招都没有了
Honestly, I have no fucking idea.
我帮不了你 克拉克
I can't help you, Clark.
能试的我都试了
As much as I tried.
这根本不是我能左右的
It's just not up to me.
我谁也救不了
I can't save anyone.
你知道吗？
You know...
我其实不想改
I don't think I want to change.
那就别改
Then don't.
我喜欢这里
I like it in here.
这么久以来
For the first time in a long time,
我第一次觉得...
I feel like I'm...
我终于找到了我的归宿
like I'm right where I'm supposed to be.
那就留下吧
Then stay.
就这么待着
Right where you are.
但你得放我走
But let me go.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起什么？
About what?
你来这儿干什么？
What are you doing in here?
这是玛丽
This is Mary.
她是咱们的心理治疗师
She's our therapist.
她正要离开
She was just leaving.
不 不
No, no.
你不用担心
You don't have to worry.
她说咱们不需要改变
She says we don't need to change.
没关系的
It's okay.
咱们的脑回路就是这样接的
It's just the way we're wired.
（由此下楼）
（干达语）“向宇宙所有族群致意”
（干达语）“愿和平永远伴随你们”
（马拉地语）“地球人民向你们传递美好的祝愿”
（全场清空 全场甩卖）
（台语）“太空的朋友们 你们好”
（台语）“吃过饭没？来我们这儿坐坐”
不
No...
（出口）
（捷克语）“亲爱的朋友们 祝你们万事如意”
（卡纳达语）“代表说卡纳达语的人们 向你们致以美好祝愿”
（拉贾斯坦语）“大家好 我们这里很幸福”
（拉贾斯坦语）“愿你们那里也同样幸福”
（英语）“来自地球儿童的问候”
"Hello from the children of planet Earth."
（古希腊语）“你们好 无论你们是谁 我们带着友谊 拜访朋友”
（葡萄牙语）“愿所有人平安幸福”
（阿卡德语）“愿一切都很好”
（俄语）“你好 欢迎你们”
（泰语）“远方土地的朋友们 你们好...”
（法语）“大家好”
你没事吧？没事吧？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
这女人是谁？
Who the fuck is that?
你是谁？
Who is it?
怎么回事？
What happened?
海盗呢？还在附近吗？
What about the pirate? Can you still see the pirate?
其他人呢？他们还在后撤吗？
And the other guys? Still going out the back?
（塞尔维亚语）“来自我们星球的诚挚祝愿”
（奥里亚语）“来自太阳系第三颗行星”
（奥里亚语）“地球的问候”
（干达语）“向宇宙所有族群致意”
（干达语）“愿和平永远伴随你们”
（马拉地语）“地球人民向你们传递美好的祝愿”
（台语）“太空的朋友们 你们好”
（台语）吃过饭没？来我们这儿坐坐
（匈牙利语）“用匈牙利语向宇宙中所有热爱和平的生命致意”
（泰卢固语）“说泰卢固语的人们向你们致以美好的祝愿”
（捷克语）“亲爱的朋友们 祝你们万事如意”
（卡纳达语）“代表说卡纳达语的人们 向你们致以美好祝愿”
（拉贾斯坦语）“大家好 我们这里很幸福”
（拉贾斯坦语）“愿你们那里也同样幸福”
（英语）“来自地球儿童的问候”
"Hello from the children of planet Earth."
你好 我叫菲尔
Hello, my name is Phil.
你是玛丽 对吧？
And you're Mary, yeah?
我想问你几个问题 主要是...
Uh... I was hoping to ask you a few questions, just for...
为了核实一些细节
some clarification on our end,
没问题吧？
if that's okay.
呃 首先...
Uh, first thing, um...
你能说说 你是怎么...
could you establish how you, uh...
进来的吗？
got in here?
我穿过了一堵墙
I walked through a wall
就在一家家具店的地下室里
in the basement of a furniture store.
你看这张照片 是这里吧？
Can you confirm that this is the location in question?
（克船长的家具帝国）
好的 你当时想购物 还是...
Okay, good. So you were shopping, or...
我当时在找人
I was looking for someone.
呃...
Um...
你找的那个人
were you looking for this man,
是他吧？
right here?
我现在在哪？
Where am I right now?
帮我确认一下行吗？
Could you just confirm for me?
这就是你要找的人吧？
Is this man right here the man you were looking for?
拜托
Please.
- 抱歉 你刚才说你叫什么？ - 菲尔
- Sorry, what was your name? - Phil.
请告诉我 菲尔 我现在在哪？
Please, Phil. Where am I?
我不...
I'm not...
我是做...呃...抱歉 我的...
I make, um... Sorry, my...
我们的公司 是生产...
Our company, we make...
核磁共振成像仪的
MRI machines.
（异步研究所）
或者...应该说
Or... I should say, um,
我们曾经是做核磁共振仪的
we used to make MRI machines.
现在不再做了
Not anymore.
那是在我们...
That was before we...
- 在我们发现那个.... - 你也进去过
- Before we found-- - You've been there.
是的 我去过
Yes, I have.
现在这成了我的工作
And now, it's my job.
我每...每天都进去
Every day, I-I go in there
试着...
and I just try to f...
试着多弄懂一点也好
try to find out ev-even a little bit more.
我在尽全力绘制地图
I-I map out areas to the best of my ability.
玛丽 我越来越坚信
And more and more, I'm convinced
在我们有生之年
that nothing in our lifetime, Mary,
甚...甚至在整个人类记录的历史中
n-nothing in-in maybe all of recorded history
没什么比这更重要了
means more than this.
可我就是没搞明白
But I don't understand it. I don't...
我...我根本说不上来
I-I can't even describe it.
这...
It...
这就好比给个没见过狗的人形容狗
It's like describing a dog to someone who's never seen a dog.
然后让那人把狗画出来
And then asking them to draw it.
现在你想让我...形容它
Now you want me to... describe it.
然后你记下来 之后呢？
And then you'll write it down, and then what?
- 玛丽... - 之后我就能走了吗？
- Mary-- - You'll let me go?
其实咱们想的一样
We all want the same thing here.
真的
We do.
咱们都只想 哪怕能多弄懂一点点
We just want to find out even a little bit more.
菲尔 我最后会怎么样？
What's gonna happen to me, Phil?
这不是我能左右的
That decision's not up to me.
那...
So...
咱们能不能就简单聊聊 就咱俩
if we could just talk, just you and me,
就像...就像普通人那样
you know, just like... just like two regular people.
咱们摊开聊聊 毕竟咱俩都进去过
We could unpack some of this, we've both been in there,
这样咱...咱们才能把话说到一块儿去
and-and-and get on the same page.
现在到处都有门在打开
There are doors opening everywhere.
我们搞不懂是啥把这些连在一起的
We don't know why or what's connecting them.
没完没了地出现
They sort of keep happening, and...
我们完全不知道怎么让它停下来...
and we don't know how to stop them...
（山脊公寓楼盘）
（《心灵之窗》）
（寻人启事 凯瑟琳·泰勒 罗博特·富兰克林）
（庭家科牙所诊 莱米饣布服）
（长克船的具家国帝）
导演
凯恩·帕森斯
编剧
威尔·苏迪克
改编自凯恩·帕森斯
系列视频
制片人
温子仁
迈克尔·克利尔
罗伯托·帕蒂诺
制片人
肖恩·利维
丹·科恩
丹·李文
制片人
奥兹·柏金斯
克里斯·费格森
制片人
彼得·切宁
詹诺·托平
科里·阿德尔森
摄影
杰里米·考克斯
剪辑
格雷格·吴
配乐
艾多·凡布利曼
凯恩·帕森斯
字幕译制
蒙太奇字幕组
字幕贡献者
翻译/校对/时间轴： 小p
校对：Ariel, Ke, Hypnotism, Balding
后期：NEST, NickCollect
蒙太奇字幕组社群
Telegram/IRC：MontageSubs
字幕许可
CC BY-NC-SA 4.0
主演
切瓦特·艾乔福 饰 家具店老板克拉克
雷娜特·赖因斯夫 饰 心理医生玛丽
主演
马克·杜普拉斯 饰 异步研究员菲尔
芬恩·班尼特 饰 小凯男友阿博
主演
卢琪塔·马克斯韦尔 饰 克拉克助理小凯
阿万·乔贾 饰 异步雇员纳伦·沃恩
罗伯特·博布罗茨基 饰 海盗版克拉克
凯恩·帕森斯
导演作品
（A24影业）
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by Love